ng generate

Generates and/or modifies files based on a schematic.

Commands:
  ng g <schematic>              Run the provided schematic.  [default]
  ng g app-shell                Generates an application shell for running a server-side version of an app.
  ng g application [name]       Generates a new basic application definition in the "projects" subfolder of the workspace.  [aliases: app]
  ng g class [name]             Creates a new, generic class definition in the given project.  [aliases: cl]
  ng g component [name]         Creates a new, generic component definition in the given project.  [aliases: c]
  ng g config [type]            Generates a configuration file in the given project.
  ng g directive [name]         Creates a new, generic directive definition in the given project.  [aliases: d]
  ng g enum [name]              Generates a new, generic enum definition in the given project.  [aliases: e]
  ng g environments             Generates and configures environment files for a project.
  ng g guard [name]             Generates a new, generic route guard definition in the given project.  [aliases: g]
  ng g interceptor [name]       Creates a new, generic interceptor definition in the given project.
  ng g interface [name] [type]  Creates a new, generic interface definition in the given project.  [aliases: i]
  ng g library [name]           Creates a new, generic library project in the current workspace.  [aliases: lib]
  ng g module [name]            Creates a new, generic NgModule definition in the given project.  [aliases: m]
  ng g pipe [name]              Creates a new, generic pipe definition in the given project.  [aliases: p]
  ng g resolver [name]          Generates a new, generic resolver definition in the given project.  [aliases: r]
  ng g service [name]           Creates a new, generic service definition in the given project.  [aliases: s]
  ng g service-worker           Pass this schematic to the "run" command to create a service worker
  ng g web-worker [name]        Creates a new, generic web worker definition in the given project.

Arguments:
  schematic  The [collection:schematic] to run.  [string]

Options:
  --help         Shows a help message for this command in the console.  [boolean]
  --interactive  Enable interactive input prompts.  [boolean] [default: true]
  --dry-run      Run through and reports activity without writing out results.  [boolean] [default: false]
  --defaults     Disable interactive input prompts for options with a default.  [boolean] [default: false]
  --force        Force overwriting of existing files.  [boolean] [default: false]
